Christopher J. Warner II, PhD

linkedin.com/in/chris-warner-II

cwarner@berkeley.edu
chris-warner-ii.github.io

Summary

Computational neuroscientist and biophysicist with a passion for data science and machine learning. With a decade of expertise in the field, I enjoy systems level thinking and excel where technical ability and creativity intersect to bring various inputs together into algorithm solutions.

Skills

Expertise: Building machine learning algorithms (neural networks, regression, classification, clustering), dynamical systems modelling, Graph Theory, Bayesian inference, visual neuroscience and image processing, time-series analysis

Technology: Python, MATLAB, Labview, Mathematica, R, C++, Git, Docker, AWS, [Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, ...]

Experience

CODA Biotherapeutics

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022

Machine Learning Engineer, Consultant

- Delivered full ML algorithm to predict interactions between proteins and drugs including NLP implementation
- Interfaced with biologists to guide protein synthesis; incorporating their feedback to guide model development
- Transitioned project into production by leveraging cloud computing, containerization and process engineering

University of California, Berkeley

Sep 2011 - Sep 2019

Redwood Center for Theoretical Neuroscience, PhD Candidate

- Pioneered retina-like image segmentation algorithm based on network modularity and anisotropic diffusion
- Built Bayesian latent variable model to infer unobserved cell assembly structure in spiking neural data
- Mentored undergrad students, guiding them in projects analyzing real world social network and global trade data

MIT, Lincoln Laboratory

Sep 2005 - Feb 2009

Advanced RF Techniques & Systems Group, Electrical Engineer

- Spearheaded radar program through hardware dev, software integration, testing, data collection, analysis and results
- Created statistical analysis pipeline to detect and classify moving targets under foliage using radar signature
- Tested, fielded, maintained and documented electronic moving target simulator units for radar system calibration

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Ph.D., Biophysics and Computational Neuroscience

Ohio State University

B.S., Physics

Berkeley, CA
Sep 2011 - Sep 2019
Columbus, OH
Sep 2001 - Jul 2005

Selected Publications

Warner, C., Ruda, K., Sommer, F.: Probabilistic latent variable model to detect structure in binary data. (2022) arXiv:2201.11108

Warner, C., Sommer, F.: A Model for Image Segmentation in Retina. (2020) arXiv: 2005.02567

Extras

- Musician, producer & sound engineer: self-produced an album of original songs I wrote, performed and recorded
- Self-led, creative, technical: stealth startup exploring computational poetry and lyric analysis in phoneme space
- Passionate about mindfulness, meditation & psychology: a growth mindset, geared towards embracing challenge